♫ In an optimistic future
♫ Next Sunday A.D.
♫ There was a guy named Joel
♫ Not too different from you or me
♫ He worked at Gizmonics Institute
♫ Just another face in a red jumpsuit
♫ He did a good job cleaning up the place
♫ But his bosses didn't like him
♫ So they shot him into space
♫ We'll send him cheesy movies
♫ The worst we can find (la-la-la)
♫ He'll have to sit and watch them all
♫ And we'll monitor his mind (la-la-la)
♫ Now keep in mind Joel can't control
♫ Where the movies begin or end (la-la-la)
♫ Because he used those special parts
♫ To make his robot friends
♫ Robot Roll Call: (Come on, let's go)
♫ Cambot (Pan left)
♫ Gypsy (Hi girl)
♫ Tom Servo (What a cool guy)
♫ Croooow (You little wisecracker)
♫ If you're wondering
how he eats and breathes
♫ And other science facts (la-la-la)
♫ Then repeat to
yourself, it's just a show
♫ I should really just relax
♫ For Mystery Science Theater 3000 ♫
(mechanical noise)
- Oh, blergh, yuck, it's
so cold in my mouth,
and it tastes like it might be Cabernet.
- Hey, kiddo, that's good stuff, come on!
- Yeah, it's got one
quarter cleansing cream.
- Yeah!
- Now, that's dumb (cries).
- Hey, everybody.
It's a bad day around here.
It's annual Wash and Wax Day,
the most dreaded day of all.
You can't go near Joel
or he'll scrub you up
to a pink pulp!
- Oh, hi, everybody.
Welcome to the SOL.
It's really lucky you happened by.
It's our annual Wash and Wax Day.
It's one of the funnest days of all!
- Okay, now, Tom, if you can hear me,
you'd want to close your mouth.
The buffers are coming by!
- Isn't it horrifying?
- Bl-bl-bl-blr!
- Okay, Tom, you're almost done.
I need Crow T. Robot.
Okay, Crow T. Robot, where are you?
- You'll never take me alive!
(upbeat music)
♫ Glibby glob, glibbly glob a
du bee low low low low low ♫
(laughs) Boy, I feel great!
That was just wonderful!
Hey, who wants to go for a walk?
♫ Red boys are delicious, delicious
♫ Candy-colored love ♫
- Shut up! Shut up!
Joel, make him stop!
- I'm sorry, your what hurts?
- Oh, come on, Crow, take it easy.
You made it through.
You're going to be okay.
Come on, I'll give you a Zagnut bar
if you can simmer down.
- No!
- How about another Nutter Butter
peanut butter sandwich cookie?
- No!
- Well, what do I have to
do to make it all better?
- I want you to beat up Tom!
- Oh, hey, you've got your
hands full with that one, huh?
Well, gotta go!
♫ Give me a head with hair
♫ Long, beautiful hair ♫
- Tom, come back here.
The Mads are calling.
- Yeah.
- Huh? What?
- Sail on, Servo.
I love a robot with panache.
- Yeah, right, whatever.
Well, Joel, everyone knows that design
is the combination of
two separate elements.
That's why we've taken interior design
and matched it with household pests
and come up with something we like to call
Decorator Roaches.
- Yes, roaches.
Fashions come and go,
but roaches are forever.
Our invention exchange this
week is Swatch Roaches.
Now for you southwest
enthusiasts, we have this
little number I like to call La Cucaracha.
(laughs) Get it?
Of course you do.
And for the sports
enthusiast in your life,
we have the 49ers roach,
complete with colors.
And over here, we have
the Peter Max roach.
- Hey, I found a roach we
haven't categorized yet.
Purple and gold, and
it's got a little skimpy
mustache on it.
- My God, you found the Prince roach!
Frank, sign him up for
Penny of the Month Club.
Say, I didn't catch your name.
- Uh, Steve.
Steve Reeves.
- Steve Reeves?
- Steve Hercules Reeves?
Wow!
- Frank!
Say, you're not going to believe this.
Talk about serendipitous experiences.
We're showing one of your movies today.
- Nu-uh!
- Well, uh-huh!
- Oh, that's great.
I'm glad you're all happy
about the Prince roach.
Look, I'm just going to cut out of here.
I'll bill you for all the work, all right?
- Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Joel, why don't you go on
with your Invention Exchange?
- Well, sirs, our Invention Exchange
is the Steve-o-meter.
- No relation to Steve Reeves.
- Right.
Well, Steve Allen, as you know,
is the author of over 300
books and short stories.
- Over 4,000 pop songs.
- The board game, Blow Your Own Horn.
- Yeah, there are so many
things that Steve Allen
has thought of.
That's why we came up
with the Steve-o-meter.
- There is the world that is known.
There is the unknown.
And there is what Steve knows.
- Right, exactly.
So, what you do is if you
thought of a new idea,
you run the Steve-o-meter over it,
and if it buzzes, well,
Steve's already thought of it.
What have you got for us here, Crow?
- Oh, okay.
It's an extremely simple and
economical desalinization
process for seawater.
- That's something new.
- Oh, okay, let's run the
Steve-o-meter over it.
(electronic music)
Oh, no, he's thought--
- Oh, rats!
- Of it already.
- Well, how about this, Joel?
A series of novels about
me and Jayne Meadows
solving murders together!
- Hmm, let's run this.
(electronic music)
Oh, I'm sorry.
- How does it do that?
- Well, here's my invention, my idea.
It's the Steve-o-meter.
I'll just run the Steve-o-meter
over the Steve-o-meter.
(electronic music)
Oh, no, he's thought of that, too!
He's everywhere!
- That's so great, Steve.
I really appreciate that.
You are one cool breed
of cat, let me tell you.
Hey, Steve, check this out, huh?
Roach burial, huh? (laughs)
- Ooh, why, you, little...
Ooh! Ooh!
Talk about the movie.
- Oh, all right.
This is the first or second?
- [Voiceover] Second.
- This is the second movie that I did,
Hercules Unchained.
It's a much younger Steve Reeves.
And let me tell you, on this set,
I toasted more than one brain cell,
if you know what I'm saying.
- [Voiceover] Push the button.
- All right, push the button.
Here you go.
- Movie sign, Steve Allen
thought of that, too!
(loud screaming)
(mechanical noise)
- Hmm, hmm, hmm.
- Oh, looking interesting.
Hmm, hmm.
- Lux Films, for dishes.
- Compagnie.
- Steve Reeves and The Vandellas.
- Steve Allen thought of that.
- OH.
- Unchained Hercules.
♫ Oh, Hercules, my darling ♫
- Did that happen?
- Oh, get technical.
(soft melancholic music)
♫ Sylvia's mother said ♫
- Quiet, Doctor Hook.
- Oh, hmm.
- More sunscreen in aisle seven, sir.
- (chuckles) Oh, I know this movie.
It's "White Men Can't Row."
- Hey, you guys, bad news, the captain
wants to waterski.
My dad told me that one.
- That's pretty funny.
- It's funny.
- Hmm.
- Hey, if you like
Giorgio, you'll love Primo.
♫ Sylvia ♫
- Stop it.
- Oh, yeah.
- I'm long.
(humming)
- If you think he's long, try me, longest.
- Long, longer, longest.
How fast do you figure we're going, Bob?
- Strike a pose.
- Nothing to it.
- I'm tied to the mast.
- Cranky Avalonian slave
ship bingo (chuckles).
- Whoa, Orphil Kidjojapus.
Ooh, I was wondering where that came from.
- Raise the oars, men!
- Raise high the roof beam, carpenter!
- Bravo Bava.
- This movie brought to you
by the letters A, B, and C.
(speaking gibberish)
- Throw over the anchor!
- Why don't you do anything around here?
(chuckling)
Hey, that's the laundry!
Bye, Mr. Hoffa.
- Hey.
(imitating trumpet music)
- Next week, on Genesis 2.
- It's a wagon train.
- [Voiceover] This is the land of Attica.
- Attica, Attica, Attica!
- What new adventures
await Hercules in this,
his native land?
- I get the feeling
you're going to tell us.
- [Voiceover] Many months
ago, he set out alone,
and now he returns with Iole, his bride.
- Hey, stop feeding my bride.
- [Voiceover] Accompanying
Hercules and Iole
to the city of Thebes
will be the young Ulysses,
son of Laërtes.
- Hey, I'm still in here!
- [Voiceover] Now they must bid farewell
to their comrades who have shared
their dangerous adventures
of the last two years.
- Farewell, comrades.
- [Voiceover] Tiphys, dauntless
pilot of the Argonaut.
- And master of knots.
- He thinks he looks like Walter Matthau.
- [Voiceover] Laërtes, the
restless ruler of Ithaca.
- Goes through a lot of skin bronzer.
- [Voiceover] Argo, who
constructed the ship
that served them all so well.
- You bring to Thebes the
most beautiful girl in Jialco.
- Thank you, feces.
- Certainly.
- I'd love to see if anyone
can put him in chains.
- (clears throat) Yeah.
- All ready, Hercules.
- [Laërtes] I ask you this
one favor, because I fear
your judgment is mature.
- Is the horse talking?
- [Laërtes] To be to him like a mother.
Ulysses is only a child
who thinks he's a man
and he'll need you.
- I think he knows.
You'll behave?
- Don't take it seriously.
It's only Father.
- Now, you listen to me.
- Excuse me, but you don't have to worry.
- There, you see?
He has no respect!
- What are these?
- No respect!
- [Laërtes] In time, use one of these.
Carefully tie a message
to the leg of a pigeon
and he'll bring it to me.
- But what are you doing
with my pigeons here?
A present.
They were hers.
Penelope got them at Samos.
- [Laërtes] That's true.
And they'll always fly
back to Ithaca no matter
where you release them.
- What if you release them in Ithaca?
- [Laërtes] And then
discover that these pigeons
can transport the news
quicker than we can.
You will see that the world
will be very different.
- It's only that most
of us feel your pigeons
are better to eat (laughs).
- Farewell, Hercules.
- I don't get it.
- Take care of my son.
- Is it my wife you entrust him to or me?
Here she is.
- Let's bring her out again (whistling).
- Come, help me up.
- Oh, I almost forgot.
- Underwear.
You'll need it.
- This lute, it's from Orpheus.
- Who's that for?
If you expect to play the
lute with those hands,
(Ulysses laughs)
it's for your wife.
- Liar, liar.
Lute's on fire. (chuckles)
- Hmm, looks like a giant egg cutter.
- I will practice.
- Pring.
Well, I was going to
read on the trek, but--
- Please thank him for me.
- Of course.
- Throw this in the
bags marked garage sale.
- Hmm.
- Farewell, Ulysses.
Heed the teachings of Hercules
because one day you will--
- Goodbye, Father.
- I know, so I can get into a good school.
- Hurry, Hercules.
Otherwise we'll all be crying.
(horses neighing)
- Be careful, my son.
- [Ulysses] I will, father!
- Boy, it sure would be
hard to leave all that, huh?
- Have fun storming the castle!
To thy own self be true!
Oh, watch out for that curve!
- Hmm, the high chaparral.
♫ Pom, pom, pom, pom, here comes the king
♫ Here comes the big number one
♫ Here comes ♫
♫ Oh, ho, the Wells Fargo ♫
Come on, everybody!
♫ Oh, ho, the Wells ♫
Oh.
- Tomorrow, we'll see the city of Thebes.
- Oh, big deal, Dad.
- We can tell them all about it.
We want you to know that
we've been listening to you.
We know that the king is Oedipus.
- Who's a fine man.
- And as for Thebes, it's tremendous,
all spacious and rich.
- And the stadium and the
baths and the palaces,
it must be heaven if you
listen to Hercules talk.
(both laugh)
- And the baths and the
malls and the baths and the--
- I don't know what you're talking about.
- I don't get it.
- Now you'll see what a real city is like.
Why, you'll hardly believe your eyes.
- They've got sports bars, you know.
- Manners and courtesy
of the people alone.
- And the baths.
- People bristling with anger.
- Who are those guys?
(loud coughing)
- And their manners are most exquisite.
- They're Argives.
What are they doing in Attica?
- Why worry about it?
- The Argives are fighters.
They live on war.
They thrive on massacres.
- But wasn't their commander a Theban?
Let's go a little faster.
- I will show them.
- Do you want to go faster?
Woo!
- Hercules, that ceremony
you went through,
the bonds of matrimony.
Now you're married.
Drive carefully.
- (chuckles) I'm grateful, Ulysses.
Thanks for the reminder.
- But shut up.
- Oh!
- Who you calling ho?
- So that's the way it is.
Now you're playing games with me.
All right, then.
Have your fun.
I want to rest.
(laughter)
- He ran out of body grease
and he gets all crabby.
- Ha! Ha!
- Hmm. Gee.
Looks like Poppin' Fresh muffins.
- How buttery.
- He's talking to himself.
♫ Nur, nur, nur
♫ Nur, nur, nu-nur ♫
♫ In the jungle, the mighty jungle ♫
(humming)
♫ We all went down to Montreal ♫
♫ Love was in those eyes ♫
♫ Hercules couldn't perform ♫
- Shut up about that.
♫ 'Cause he's using steroids ♫
- She's using the Mel Bay method.
♫ You remain your words to me ♫
- Thank you. Next!
♫ Tell me you are mine
♫ Tell me in the starlight
♫ Last night I was in your arms ♫
- Hey, this is a family show.
♫ My heart still dances ♫
- Herc is trying to sleep back here.
♫ By that evening star
♫ I will walk ♫
♫ Yippi-yi-yo ♫
(imitating dog howling)
♫ Forevermore ♫
- She's going to crack her makeup.
♫ Just you and I
♫ By the evening star ♫
- I think I'll fall on my spear.
(upbeat music)
- Hey! Hey!
Stop a moment, strangers.
This valley is mine.
And no one passes through this valley
unless I say so, and they pay a price.
Yes, this valley is Antaeus'!
And you'll do anything because I say so.
(loud thud)
- Ooh, ow.
All right, go ahead.
- Now, tell me, do you have any gold
hidden in the carriage?
- And the first thing
I'll take are your horses.
Go unharness them for me.
- Hercules! Hercules!
- Oh, I want to sleep.
- Oh, thanks, Hercu-wuss.
- Come on, you get down.
I said I want the horses.
- You take advantage of us
just because you're Antaeus.
- And why not?
Just a boy and a lady.
Come on, now, get down!
- I'll show you what a boy can do.
- I can fly!
- Nice recovery.
- Hercules, he'll kill him!
- I'm so sleepy, I can't
seem to keep awake.
- Oh, that'd be the definition of sleepy.
- Who are you speaking to?
- To my husband.
- And what's he doing?
- He was dozing.
- Dozing, was he?
I'll wake him up.
- I wouldn't do that.
- I know the sleepy husbands,
or is he just frightened?
- He might awaken when he sees you.
- Husband.
- You're my valentine.
- Hey, you, husband.
That's right.
Kiss your lady goodbye and pass on.
I'm adopting the lady.
- Is that right?
- Yes, I'm taking her.
It's my pleasure.
I like her very much, the lady.
- And what does she say about that?
- She'd like a new husband,
like every woman (laughs).
- Ah, awkward moment.
- Hercules.
(loud laughter)
- Hercules!
- He makes Andre the Giant
look like Paul Newman.
- They all turn out to be just like that.
All right, come on and fight.
- What would happen if he really hit him?
- Why is he wearing a bath mat?
- Maybe the next time,
you'll treat me better.
Come on, let's be on our way.
- Well, break out the chest, please.
- He sees the bright side of everything.
(loud laughter)
- You've got a tough skin.
(suspenseful music)
- Lambada, the forbidden dance.
- You know, I had a dream like this once.
- Watch it, I'm wearing my retainer.
- Lower.
I got it, ah.
(suspenseful music)
- Ah, I saw Lucy do this Mr. Mooney once.
- Ooh.
- Oh, I fell on my keys.
- Is this a half nelson or a full nelson?
- Nah, it looks like a Ricky Nelson.
- No, it's just Nelson.
- Ooh.
What scares me is they don't have showers.
- Okay, you can have me.
I give up.
Rondo Hatton.
- You know, Rondo's good,
'cause you can slam him
down hard.
See?
- Yeah.
- Oh, I see London, I see France.
Huh?
(loud laughter)
- Snicker snag on him, dangle spit.
Come on, Herc!
- Worried about his nipple.
- Any questions?
- Come on, Iole.
(loud laughter)
- Here we go.
- Yeah, I wish he was on our side.
He seems really fun.
(loud laughter)
- He might be a god.
- I don't care if he's Pluto.
I'm going to knock that
silly grin off his face
once and for all.
- I tell you, Hercules,
it must be Antaeus,
son of the earth goddess.
When he touches the ground,
he marshals his forces!
- So that's it.
Then I'll change my way of fighting.
- That's who he said he was.
- Let me down.
Just put me down and you'll see.
- Put me down, put me down!
Mom, Mom, this isn't fun anymore.
Mom!
- I'll spank you.
- Put me down!
Let me down!
(water splashing)
- I've got tubes in my ears!
- There.
- Thanks, friend.
I haven't showered since Zeus was a pup.
- Go on!
But one day you'll have to pass through
my valley again!
- Not after they build the Interstate.
- Virginians, starring James Drury,
brought to you by Nabisco.
- Well, thanks for beating up Antaeus.
I really didn't want to be his wife.
- Just a little wait further.
- There's a gas station.
- I hope we'll be able to rest there.
- I know this forest very well.
Why shouldn't we?
It's quiet here.
They say the gates to the inferno
are hidden among its trees.
- On Broadway.
- But Hercules, look!
- Oh, they're tailgating up ahead.
It must be a Packer game.
- [Hercules] It's the first
time I ever saw anyone here.
- Everybody's making out here.
- Ooh, I'm getting wet.
- Hurry then.
- He's putting a car cover on a horse?
- Stop, what do you want?
- Let her alone.
She's come to keep us company.
What's your name?
- You'll soon find out.
Don't worry.
- Oh, look at that.
She's beginning to fight.
I better tame you.
- Boy, he's bald.
- Not really, no.
- I'm with the big guy, sorry.
- Edward Arnold?
- But wasn't that Hercules?
- He's shorter than his pictures.
(loud laughter)
- Giddy with violence.
- And then we ducked into a little cafe.
- Be quiet.
- [Oedipus] You and
Eteocles, my own children,
plotted to steal my kingdom
and share it between you.
- Mr. Hart, you're late.
- You and your brother have
driven me out of my kingdom.
Only here can I find asylum,
and here I shall die.
- Oedipus.
- Cut, cut.
Hercules, please!
- I know that voice.
It recalls a time in my
life when I was happier.
- Look, it's me, Hercules.
(coughing)
- I came at a bad time, didn't I?
- To me, you are still
the faithful Hercules.
- What are you doing here?
- I'm Ralph Richardson.
- You're Polynices.
- I remember you from the gym.
- You have left Thebes?
- It was not up to me.
My sons thought it better
I renounce the throne,
and so at last, I did, so
that he and his brother
might rule.
- No!
- Give the throne to his brother.
But now Polyneces tells
me that the year is up.
- The god of exposition.
- Look, Father, it's my turn now.
And it's plain to see
just what his brother
wants to do.
♫ It's my turn ♫
- Now, he won't cede to his brother.
He promised to do so.
Now that his year is up, he
has driven his brother away.
- In his new car!
- What do you want of your father?
- Just to pardon us.
- I'm not going to be deceived!
I know just what he wants,
to get to keep the throne
with the help of the Argives.
The throne carries only tragedy.
It can bring no happiness.
Your city will fall
between these two brothers.
- So what I'm hearing here, Polynices,
is you're angry with your father.
- Thebes will be destroyed
and its men will be slain,
and its women, so long as
these two ambitious rulers
get what they want now.
- Now, listen to me, Polynices.
I've known you since you were a child
and I respect your father.
Otherwise, I would exact
justice for Thebes.
- Crossfire.
On the left, Hercules.
- I'll go to your brother
and try to convince him
to respect the pact you made.
- Pact, shmack.
- It's a noble thought
that you have, Hercules,
but my sons will listen to no one.
- But Thebes is my city.
We must spare our people this bloodshed.
- And we built this city on rock and roll.
- Successful in overcoming the madness
of these men, or I'll believe that I--
- Hercules.
- Hercules, am decided by the gods.
- Echo, echo, echo.
- Well, Polynices.
- Well, I can give you a
small part in the chorus,
but that's all.
- If you pass the pencil test.
- If it's better, go with Eteocles, go on.
- I grant you six days.
Let me know if you can
make peace between us.
- At the end of those six
days, we'll march our army
against the Thebans.
(mechanical noise)
♫ And now to Eden
♫ Hey, brother ♫
Haha, Tom, consider the grape.
- Oh, I will.
- So delicate, so firm (laughs).
- You guys, I don't see
why I have to be the one
to peel these grapes.
You know, it's really kind of hard.
- And he calls himself
a hedonist (laughs).
- You know what, I think
it's great that Gypsy
had built this set and
made these costumes for us,
just so she can put on our show.
You guys should do something like that.
- You know, you're right.
Starting right now, I'm going to roll over
and eat more grapes.
- Oh, here she comes.
She's beautiful.
- Hey, looking good, Gypsy.
- Thank you.
And now for a little song in G.
♫ Last night
- Like a beautiful breeze.
♫ Last night ♫
- So what's she supposed to be, Joel?
- I'm the Hellenistic ideal.
- Oh.
♫ Last night ♫
(loud thud)
- You know, folks, you
just don't hear music
like that anymore.
(loud thud)
- You know, folks, I have
a feeling this is going
to go on like this, so
why don't you run on ahead
into the commercial?
We'll catch up.
♫ Last night, I couldn't
get to sleep at all ♫
- Hey, Joel, am I the only one who notices
I'm not eating a grape?
♫ Last night ♫
Oh, missed.
(upbeat music)
- Hmm, that was good.
- The castle of my father.
- Welcome to my house, Eteocles.
- Two words, Hercules: French doors.
- And you will take the lady with you?
- No, Ulysses will come with me.
- Same thing.
- Ulysses?
Now, who is he?
- Ulysses, son of Laërtes, King of Ithaca.
- A king without soldiers?
I'm not interested.
Take this.
- Put it where the sun don't shine.
- You can tell my brother this.
From now on, what he asks, I will do.
- You've been lifting.
What's your max?
- That's what you're here for, isn't it?
And tomorrow morning, I'll send servants,
goods, and provisions.
- And lawyers, guns, and money.
- If you live alone here in Thebes,
you'll grow impatient.
- Need a roommate?
- Thank you.
- I'll guard Iole until he gets home.
- Ah, then I'm certain
she'll be all right.
- Ouch, grr.
- Creon is the purest and most
intelligent man in Thebes.
- And Creon's nontoxic.
- I'll have Hercules in his way.
I bid you goodbye (laughs).
- Everyone's a comedian.
- Well, I guess it's catch-as-catch-can.
- Next week on Alias Hercules and Ulysses.
- Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow, ow!
- Industry, big and bold.
♫ We are running horses
♫ We are fancy free ♫
- And that's when I won
first prize at the fair.
- Let me out of this cage.
(laughter)
- Well, we must be there.
The music's dying down now.
(laughs) What a fun day.
- Look, cotton.
Meanwhile, Flavius, son of
Magor, is feuding with Crylon.
- I'm pretty sure this
is a Star Trek set here.
- Looks like a Maxfield Parrish painting.
Hmm, kind of.
- Something about this place.
- Reminds me of Appleton.
- Look, I'm hungry.
- Make sure and take good aim.
And remember--
- The distance, the force of the wind,
the speed of the target.
You just decide how you like it
before I get back.
- Well said.
I'll go start the fire up.
And don't come back empty-handed!
- Make sure of the vacuum.
- Well that bird will be
in the next county by now.
- [Voiceover] These are the
waters of forgetfulness.
Those who drink of them will forget all.
(horses neighing)
- He's right, you know.
- What was that?
Uh, who do I belong to?
Eh, one of my arms died.
I forgot how to breathe.
- I've forgotten
everything, but I can't seem
to get "Afternoon Delight" out of my mind.
♫ Sky rockets in flight ♫
♫ Last night ♫
(horses neighing)
Do I hear Dorothy Lamour?
- Hardly any animals
were hurt in the making
of this movie.
- It's a fine one!
- Mr. Grinch.
- Hey, Ulysses, Hercules drank from
the fountain of forgetfulness!
Bye, gotta go, see you.
- Where are they going?
- We're going to Dayton's warehouse sale!
- It's so crunchy,
you'll do a triple take.
- Nice foley work.
Sounds like he's running
on a gym floor (chuckles).
- Oh, no. Oh, no.
It's the thing!
- You know, I just know
there's a hot chick
around here somewhere.
- Let's see, is it live or is it Memorex?
I've forgotten.
- Iole!
- What's happening?
- Are you having one of your episodes?
- Put a wallet under my tongue.
- What's a wallet?
- Where are you, Iole?
- Hercules, what's the matter?
- Iole!
Can't you hear her voice?
Can't you hear her?
- It's difficult.
- No, it's not difficult.
- But I don't hear anyone.
- I think it's from Anything Goes.
- Hercules, look at me.
It's Ulysses.
Hercules, listen to me!
Hercules!
- No, he didn't forget how
to be rude, now, did he?
- Well, this is as good a place as any.
You know what they say.
You can only rent the
waters of forgetfulness.
- Oh, yeah.
(loud crash)
- I told you, truffles, right?
I'm right every time.
- James Brolin.
You really are strong.
- I forgot how my muscles work.
- Hehe, now I can pose
him in funny positions.
- Hercules!
- Blood, sweat, and tears!
(imitating trumpet music)
- Just playing Narcissus here.
- Ulysses, it's the
waters of forgetfulness!
Now his chest won't remember a thing!
- Somebody here dial IXII.
(imitates siren blaring)
We're the ambulance, pretty much.
- Who are you?
Who are you?
- Sal Mineo.
- Answer me.
Taking no chances.
Traveling alone with a deaf mute.
- Oh, I'm glad you think I'm a deaf mute.
Oh, nuts.
- And you, come along.
Come on!
- My hinder!
- It sounds like a...
Oh, forget it.
♫ Du du dududu ♫
Sounds like a flower drum
song all of a sudden.
- Oh, I did not need to see that.
- Oh, my eye!
♫ Flying high ♫
- James' adventures...
Oh, you know the drill.
- Sleepover, huh?
I see.
- I am beat.
- I like this.
Got in a seven and a half?
- Better see.
- Rachel Ward.
- Now, test him.
We'll know if he's deaf or not.
- Uh-oh.
Let's see here (clears throat).
So I'm a big Marlee Matlin fan.
How about you?
Huh, boy, I sure love
the "Miracle Worker."
- Do you still have any doubts?
- I almost let out a yell for myself!
- My scalp actually tingled, sir!
Good work, sir!
- Hey, I can hear the ocean.
Oh, it is the ocean.
- Evan Rue, the early years.
- Jeez, how deeply did he drink
from the waters of forgetfulness?
- Hey, thanks for helping me move Hercules
this weekend.
I've got beer and pizza for you.
♫ It's a Sealy Posturepedic
morning, yeah ♫
- Oh, they're going to dump
him on his parents' steps.
- Oh, that's sad.
- Hmm?
- Oh, they're taking him to the Tiki Room.
He'll be fine.
♫ Oh wee oh ♫
- Shoot, I'm out of triple sec.
- They're arriving.
♫ Barbarella psychedella ♫
They're here.
- Really?
You think I'm gray?
- Don't desert me, please?
Don't desert me.
- I was just going to go to the bathroom.
Talk about abandonment issues.
- Turn the fan on.
Oh, sorry.
- This place is even cooler
than Rhoda's apartment, huh?
- Miss World Italy!
- Postage due on this one.
- Inspect before you sign.
- Hercules, the Theban, Your Highness.
- I gathered.
- Hercules.
- This is his servant,
just a poor deaf mute.
- Hi! Oh, shoot!
- I beg you.
Listen to me.
- Take him away.
- I just love Italian beef.
- No, Omphale!
You told me you loved me!
Save me, Omphale!
Help me!
- Help me, Spark, help me!
- Yeah, we know, et tu Brute.
- Yeah.
(upbeat music)
- Blood, sugar, sex, magic.
- There's something I'd like to ask you.
- Is that a Jantzen suit you're wearing?
- And what would you like to ask me?
- What's happened to me?
I don't remember anything.
- Except my scout number.
- Not even who I am.
- And is that so important?
- Well, I'm pretty sure
I got a paycheck coming.
- I don't know, I can't remember anything.
- Oh, I do.
- Do you know this boy?
- Why?
- Think hard.
- I can't. It hurts.
- I've never seen him before.
- I was in Austria during the war.
Okay, bye.
- Come sit beside me.
- Move your big old leg.
♫ Take the ribbon from my hair ♫
- Who is that boy?
- Your servant.
- You win the crazy award.
- My servant?
- Yes.
- I swear by the gods that I--
- Do you want me to believe
that you can't remember
that you're the king of this land,
that you're my husband?
- So take out the garbage!
- So, those are his daughters then, huh?
- Hmm.
- There will be no seating
until the first intermission.
- Team Reebok.
- This is our interpretation of spring.
- Thanks for the good seats.
- You take that two-drink
minimum seriously, don't you?
- Jessie, now Jerome.
- Cassie!
(soft music)
- Jazz hands, jazz hands!
- Step and turn and--
- Ladies and gentlemen, Deney Terrio!
- Oh, this must be the headliner.
- Oh, boy, I hope she's
in a body stocking.
- Ordinary pantyhose are
okay under funky clothes
but gentlemen prefer Hanes.
- Hmm. Ooh.
♫ Wawawawawawawa ♫
- How sneaky, like, where'd she go?
Ah, there she is.
Oh, like, who can't do that?
Oh, I'm standing on my hair.
Could somebody help me?
(soft music)
- So does this thing heat up at all?
- Hey, this is not my beautiful house.
This is not my beautiful wife.
How did I get here?
- Ah, the chicken dance, very nice.
- That's what I did in my act.
- Hey, wait a minute.
Her skin has a zipper.
- Timber!
- Let's see.
It snowed real bad and we got snowed in,
and Murray had to stay over, and then.
- This is jogging my memory.
- It's jogging something.
- Anyway, I like the idea of being a king.
By the way, what's my name?
- Who's my daddy?
Was he rich?
Was he rich like me?
- What difference does it make?
- Nothing.
It's just what you called me.
- To me, your name is love.
- Bunny love?
(romantic music)
- Haha, I'm beginning to like this place.
- And me?
- And you.
- Now, you, I can take or leave.
- Most of all.
(loud clanging)
- Hey, in 2000 years, that
will be worth something!
- What are they doing?
- Ooh, you taste like Diaphemes.
- What are they up to, Joel?
- Let's pack it up, girls.
Our work here is finished.
♫ Tadum ♫
- Bless this mess?
Oh.
(soft music)
- Hey, this is the girls' dorm!
- Ah, this is really cute, Karen.
Can I borrow it sometime?
- Hey, all the boys have to register
at the front desk.
- What is this, Iole?
It was in the bottom of the chest.
Does it mean anything
for you and Hercules?
- What's that supposed to mean?
- Will you be still?
- Going to cry now, baby?
- When is he coming?
- He's only been gone about three days.
- Because of his treaty, you know.
Many times you can't
settle them right away.
- Yes, I see.
If he's delayed, it's something logical.
But I feel so anxious when I don't hear.
- We should have at least
gotten a pigeon by now.
- I'll stay only until tomorrow morning,
and then I'll go to see
if I can locate him.
- I'll call the finder of lost loves.
- All of a sudden, it's paint your wagon.
♫ Peace on earth was all he said
♫ Du, du, dudududu ♫
- Hey, I can see my house from here!
- Bird lives, woo!
- I thought I say Ulysses.
I did it!
I did see Ulysses.
- You guys wait here.
- Hmm, I was just doing
the dishes, hmm-hmm.
- Come on, you're going to work, now, now!
- I've got to finish these dishes first.
(suspenseful music)
- My boy, I have discovered
something very important.
- This really bugs me.
- Up to now, I've been
making one big mistake.
- Hey, is he turtlewaxing him?
- And stay awake at night.
Otherwise, you'll lose the
best part of your life.
- I can see you've been really
thinking deep here, sir.
- Hey, it's tea.
You know, that's hard to find around here.
(soft music)
- Is it prepared?
- Hmm.
Dinner, Herc.
- Ah, yes.
The night was made for love.
The sun out there dulls the senses.
Enough. I'm hungry.
- Oh, I think he just
insulted the waitress.
- Haha, what a life.
(women giggling)
You wake up in the morning
without a care in the world
and nothing to do.
- Just like collecting
unemployment checks.
(loud crash)
- The heck you doing there?
- Ah, clumsy.
It looks like you did it on purpose.
- Shh!
- Let's play charades.
- Okay, I'll go along.
- Look to the left, look to the right,
stand, sit down, fight, fight, fight!
- This is the fountain of dorkiness.
- Got any ketchup for this?
- Don't tell.
- You are Hercules.
- Pff!
- What did you say?
- I forgot already.
- Hercules.
- Hercules?
What about Hercules?
- Iole.
- Go away, I don't understand a thing.
- Iole, your marriage,
Eteocles, Polynices,
the message, the perilous
war against Thebes.
- Things you'd say to Socrates.
(quick footsteps)
- Bend it.
If you can't, you'll convince me.
- If you can, you're Uri Geller.
- You're lucky I'm in
a good mood, Ulysses.
(loud grunting)
- Rats, I can't bend it.
Guess I have to stay
here with all the nymphs.
- Hit the road, Pedro.
Oh, hi, Herc.
♫ Wawawawawawa
♫ Rarararara ♫
- Good morning.
(soft music)
- Did you sleep well last night?
- Wonderfully.
I dreamt of you.
- And I'm flattered.
- And flattery will get you everywhere.
- Ah, old ball and chain (chuckles).
- So, what's on the slate today,
eating and loving, huh?
- Somehow I recall that
you had a different face.
- Yeah, it was fillers stillers.
I had to return it.
- Prettier?
- No, just different.
Blond hair, sweet smile.
- Hair growing out of your wart.
- So you've begun to
betray me in your dreams.
- Aren't you afraid that somehow
we'd displease the fates
and they'll take their revenge on us?
- I try not to think about it.
So, anyway.
- I don't want to talk about sad things
when I'm so happy.
I love you.
For me, that's all that counts.
(upbeat music)
- [Magic Voice] This is
the water of forgetfulness.
Those who drink of it will forget all.
- Huh, say, who manufactures
the water of forgetfulness anyway?
- Oh, it says here on the
bottle, Mendota Springs,
makers of the water of
forgetfulness, since, oh,
let me think.
Oh, it's on the tip of my tongue.
When was it?
- [Magic Voice] This is the
carrot shake of pretentiousness.
- Ooh, let me try that.
- [Magic Voice] Those who drink of it
will join theater companies.
- Yeah, you know, I'm doing
an anti-Columbus thing
down at the heart of the
Meat Puppet Beast Theater.
It's a real opportunity for me to stretch.
- Hey, Joel, that cup looks like
it's from Dairy Queen.
Can I have some?
- Hmm.
- [Magic Voice] This is
the blizzard of loneliness.
Those who drink of it
will sit on the beach
wearing long pants and black socks
and look for change in the sand
with a metal detector.
- I found a quarter!
- Hey, who wants gum?
- I do, I do!
- Here.
- [Magic Voice] You're eating
the fruit stripe of stability.
Those who chew it will
get a civil service job
with good benefits.
- Yup, thanks to the fruit
stripe gum of stability,
I've got a good dental plan now.
Ironic, huh?
- [Magic Voice] You are
eating the green bean
and french onion casserole of happiness.
Those who eat of it will find the serenity
that only a hot dish can bring.
- Oh, you know, I really,
really love this stuff.
It's so nutritious and
it's so good for you.
And I love my location.
It's so conveniently
located, what with the chains
and dinner theater and
the new high school,
and oh the elks lodge puts
on a wonderful fish fry
every weekend.
And we're right next
to the chain of lakes.
And we've got movie signs.
And they do the big
Chautauqua show every summer.
And they've got movie signs.
Movie sign? Oh!
(mechanical noise)
- Hot dish is filling, isn't it?
- Oh, yeah, it's so good.
- Peter, Paul, and Mary.
- And where did they find the princess?
- The Personals.
- Just planning to run away
because she couldn't stand Thebes
and she wanted to rejoin her husband.
- Walk this way.
- Stop.
- Did you hear from Hercules?
- Well, just a message on my machine.
- Not a word since he's away.
And I'll I've done was wait here alone.
And if I did run away, it was only...
I beg you to let me go to Hercules.
- And let me smoke in my room.
- That would be splendid for you two, huh?
Reunited under the tender
care of my brother Polynices.
- I don't see what you mean, sir.
- Well, it's not her fault, Eteocles.
And why blame Hercules?
Don't you see, if you let
them go to each other, then--
- Stop yelling!
Why is everybody yelling?
- You talk to me as if
I'm prepared to take leave
of my senses.
Take the woman away.
- Well, they're posing
for the Primo beer can.
- Cool.
- That's unjust, inhuman.
- I shall now arrest any
and all Theban suspected
of plotting with Polynices!
Arrest them all!
- They left, sir.
- With their goods and
families and servants!
- Can't we just arrest everyone in red?
- You who all pretend
that you want justice.
That nobody Hercules and
my friends here in court.
- Cut!
- Creon will be my example.
- What about El Marco?
- Arrest him.
- Made you look, haha.
- And now, a journey
through the lymph nodes.
- You mean, nymph lodes.
- Ooh.
- Ah, working out a new filing system.
All right.
(imitates loud snoring)
- Wake up, it's time to go to work.
Get out of bed now.
- I can't hear you, I'm sleeping and deaf.
- Get up now, it's late.
Your master's waiting for his massage.
- At two in the morning?
- Massage this, you cretin.
I mean, cretin.
(playful music)
- Creon will be played by the bassoon.
♫ Dududududu ♫
- What the heck is going on here?
♫ Dun dun dun dun dulululu dun dun ♫
- Ah, yeah, like no one's going to notice
the string on the lock.
- Here's our Hercules power wrist band.
- Nice.
(suspenseful music)
- Shh!
- Coming, Mom!
- Mm, big old jelly doughnut.
Oh, boy, I love this.
Hmm. Ah.
(suspenseful music)
(loud crash)
- You are nuttier than an
outhouse rat, you know that?
- That's the second time
you knocked over my goblet.
- How would you remember that?
- I do it for you, Hercules.
- Why is it you keep
on calling me Hercules?
- You know my name is Todd.
- Hmm, really, tore through
those bare claws, didn't you?
- I've heard that name before.
- You'll see, soon you'll remember.
- Just look at your chariot license.
- Remember what?
- It's too complicated
to explain to you now.
I beg you to avoid drinking that water.
Then you'll recover your memory
and soon we'll be able to escape.
Escape from this, why?
- Go away?
Isn't this your native land?
- You and I have been comrades.
We were captured and brought here.
I tell you that we must get out of here.
What I saw was so terrible!
- Curly Sue?
- You see, during the
day, they don't bother me.
At night, I'm put into a
cell and locked inside.
Yesterday, I was looking
for a means to get out.
- That's dippity do!
- I saw a path leading to a cave.
- Let me demonstrate.
♫ Into the woods, into the woods ♫
Dad?
(suspenseful music)
It's not that scary.
- Well, maybe.
(suspenseful music)
- Oh, it's Kim Cattrall.
- It's scary.
- Nice skort.
- Sir, please don't touch
the exhibit, please.
- Yeah!
- And then I came to another passage and
it's Madame Tussauds.
- Oh!
Now just about that time...
Are you listening to me?
Good.
Wait, this is a disco inferno!
- Hmm.
- Suddenly, people showed up.
You meet them wherever you're going.
(suspenseful music)
- Oh, hi, Rey, hi, Rel.
- Looks like a cheap Temple of Doom set.
- Ooh!
- Oh, cool, it's like a Thing maker.
- She's got Batman underwear on!
- Cool!
- You Egyptians are truly so clever
that almost certainly you'll find a way
of even preserving life.
- Life is different.
We can't create the soul of man.
- Still, it must be exciting, your work.
- Look, I just told you it's different.
- Just the man, the way he looks,
the way he stands.
- When can we expect to
get to work on Hercules?
- Well, let's see, I've
got an eight o'clock
and a nine-thirty, and oh.
- Gotta go. Bye.
Come on, girls.
- Wait, wait, come back!
You forgot your free casket!
- Was this a Remington Steel episode?
- I think so.
- I tremble with fear
at what she plans to do
with us, Hercules.
- Why should I believe you?
- I expected that.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- I'm going to ask the queen
to see if you're lying.
- Omphale will be sure to deny it.
She'll kill me, and then
what will happen to you?
I prefer to be killed by you
rather than that way.
- Why, thank you.
- I promise you, I won't speak anymore
about Hercules or Omphale.
- Ah.
Cripes, I am the Herc.
(loud clanging)
- Just set that anywhere, Herc.
- Hi, who are you?
- You jerk, you bent my lamp.
- No, you did!
- Did not.
There.
- It's still bent.
They're going to be able to tell.
(loud clanging)
He's back.
- Wahahahaha!
- I'm coo coo for cocoa puffs,
coo coo for cocoa puffs!
- A little embarrassing.
(loud giggling)
(loud laughter)
- I can't believe I liked him.
- Jeez, turning into Harpo.
- Yeah.
(women giggling)
- When Kennedys rule Greece (chuckles).
- Uh-oh, Heather's dad is here, guys.
(imitates trumpet music)
- So, now, what we've done with Hercules
is minimize his large
forehead with this flower ring
and accentuate his massive chest.
- Go away now.
I just said leave me!
- Oh, my, what happened to him?
- I never get tired of that.
- No one ever dared give
an order in my presence.
- No one else is the Herc-meister.
- Well, it's only the first time.
- Hey, it's nine-thirty, honey.
- So what are they doing?
- Oh, wow!
- Mm, he's Herculicious!
- What are they up to, Joel?
(romantic music)
- You have a strange power over me.
- Power of attorney.
- Whether it's love or not, I don't know.
- I don't think it is.
- And yet all I want
is just to be with you.
- That's the way I like it.
- Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
- Bet he says that to all the queens.
- Oh, more gushy stuff.
Hmm?
(trumpet blasting)
Ricola?
(coughing)
- What was that?
- It's my pager.
- Great queen.
- Thanks!
- Arrived with a small crew.
They want to stay here several days.
They are waiting to
present their respects.
- Tell them to go away!
Why don't they sail back to Ithaca?
We don't want visitors.
- But we have to receive them.
- Well, okay.
- It would be an offense, a grave offense.
- And is it not an offense
to me, to be abandoned?
- Oh, love Herc.
- I won't be far away.
I won't be gone long, just time enough
to pay my respects.
- And the water bill.
- Well, it's not everybody
who gets to make out
at Cypress Gardens.
- Um-hmm.
- Wait here.
I will not be gone.
- Do I look like I'm going to get up
and do something?
- What's for lunch?
- (clears throat and whistles)
- Uh-oh.
- Go on, back to your cell.
Come on now.
- Show's over, nothing to see here.
- Come on.
- The Aegean Sea has not been
gentle with us, great Queen.
- I lost it like four times.
- We have a long perilous
voyage ahead of us.
- Yeah, boo-hoo.
- Excuse us, mighty Queen,
since all that you see here
is poor and modest.
Mercy and hospitality are all that we ask.
And these gifts express
our homage and goodwill--
- These are gifts?
Don't bother wrapping.
to you for ruling the island of Lydia--
- Oh, about the old guy,
he comes with the package.
- Thank you, Laërtes, King of Ithaca.
- Hmm.
- I have already given orders
that you and your friends
will be taken to the
best wing of the palace.
- Yeah, by the ice machine.
- My men will accompany you there.
- Could your women accompany us?
- Our humble thank you.
- I thought our presentation
was pretty good,
how about you?
- [Omphale] You, what
is your name, young man?
- My name is Mrs. Norman Maine.
- I have the feeling we've
met somewhere before.
- Oh, I just have the feeling.
- While the others are
taken to their rooms,
stay a moment with me.
I would like to try and
remember where we met.
- I'm at your service.
- Oh, she always goes for the jock types.
- But I am smart, really, and I'm funny.
Oh, they never pick the old guy.
- Excuse me, I'm late for my two-thirty.
- Hercules.
- What did you say?
- Hercules?
- You mean, you don't know me?
Tell me of Ulysses.
- Who are you?
♫ Are you, are you ♫
- What does this man want from me?
- Hercules!
That's not who he is.
- You're right, Omphale.
It's just because both
Hercules and this man
are both gigantic.
But if you take another look at this man,
then it's plain to see in a moment
that we men were in error.
- I've seen Laërtes, Hercules' face.
And his figure.
This couldn't be Hercules.
- Who is this Hercules?
- A born fighter and the
greatest man in Thebes.
A hero.
- And a hell of an engineer.
- What does he have to do with me?
- Nothing.
Why, it's like water and wine.
It's bad to mix them.
- Why is everybody teasing me?
- Please go.
I'll see you later.
- Not later, right this minute.
- Who are you?
And who are you?
Ah!
- I beg your pardon.
- Please excuse us, and now
we'll retire, if we may.
- Oh, here's your gold
watch and your 401k.
- Miss Utah is a Rhode scholar who wants
world peace and that special someone.
- So, live around here much?
- I want to try this on.
- What does that have to do with me?
Pearls must have contact with the flesh
before they take their best sheen.
- The closer she gets,
the weirder she looks.
Ew!
- This necklace will
be much more beautiful.
- Well.
Ah, great sunrise.
Let's go have breakfast, fellows.
- It's the old Cedar man.
- Kind of makes you feel
small, doesn't it, Elvin?
- Pretty much.
- Now I'm ready to begin action.
A man can only live so long patiently.
- That's nice.
Ever thought of putting two
similar sentences together?
- The time is all gone.
Eteocles and Hercules
are conspiring against me
in getting the throne.
- What are you, Jim Garrison?
- I'll be king yet, and
they, all they need to see
is this army coming.
- Your army can sweep under the Thebans.
- One of the guys has a dustpan head.
- It'll be a surprise for
my friends down there.
- Certainly it will be a great
thing, beating the Thebans.
The throne is there and
the riches of the city.
- Anything, Mr. Herman.
- All right. Come on.
- Bye.
(suspenseful music)
♫ We are the men from Texaco ♫
- It's an army of porta potties.
- It's Eddie Murphy's entourage.
- No, it's a walkathon.
- How many pledges did you get?
♫ Pom pa pom
♫ Popopopom
♫ Po pom po pom ♫
Oh.
- Now, you, Macario, may take your men
to the south gate.
Oraphante, to the north gate.
- And dick, you take Watergate (laughs).
- And Theo, you'll defend Pedelipo
on his right flank and Hector on his left.
- Um, excuse me sir.
I was actually hoping to--
- Ah, Astane.
And wasn't it of you that Creon said,
"Trust that man with your soldiers."
- Everybody misquotes that.
- You'll defend the most vulnerable point,
the main gate of Thebes.
- At your command, Eteocles.
- I shall confront them.
- What, does he have his
lines written on that thing?
- On top of the sacred gate of Delphi.
- Delphi rules! Woo!
- What is that?
- Uh, the wind, sir?
- People around Thebes taking
refuge in the city, sire.
They've nowhere else to go.
- Coming into town without my saying so?
But there are too many people to feed
in Thebes already.
No, back outside!
- Listen, Eteocles.
The Thebans are getting restless.
You'll be losing their favor.
- Flavor?
- Yes, oh surely.
They prefer good old Creon.
- To markers.
- But I've got a plan for Creon.
- And it just might work.
- For now, close up the gates to the city.
Close them!
No one is to enter Thebes anymore!
- And take those ridiculous hats off!
(growling)
- They're great!
(suspenseful music)
- Hey, is this the line for the execution?
- No, we're on line for
U2 tickets, aren't we?
- Ow, my eyes!
- Ooh.
(upbeat music)
- Oh, she hasn't kissed a
man in over five minutes.
- Leave me.
- Gee, Miss Mood Swing here.
(soft footsteps)
- Why did you ask me to come here?
- I had an opening between
three and three-thirty.
- You don't really want me.
♫ Don't you want me, baby ♫
- You would never understand.
- Really?
But don't you think it's simple?
You're furious that I asked that.
And it's because you don't know the reason
for our visit.
No.
- Thank you. Dr. Freud.
- And you won't learn it from me.
- Be quiet!
- Why?
You've had enough of me?
I pity you now because you
can never hold Hercules.
- You think I don't know that?
- I curse the day he entered this palace.
- Hi, what you talking about?
- You curse the day I
entered your palace on folly.
- Huh!
- I was able to pull the threads together.
At last I know who I am.
- I'm Big Jim McLain!
(suspenseful music)
- Don't take revenge, Hercules.
- Take my wife, please.
- He wouldn't kill me.
- [Hercules] And what
makes you believe that?
- You, yourself, Hercules.
You won't kill me because
you know how much I love you.
- Plus I have a restraining order on you.
- I knew that sooner
or later I'd lose you,
and so I lost you, Hercules.
If you only knew how I've
struggled with myself
to keep from ever
falling in love with you,
but in vain, all in vain.
- If I believed you--
- That would be pretty funny (chuckles).
- I would have pity on you.
- Oh, if only my sincerity
could keep you here.
- [Hercules] Get up!
- Glycerin.
- It's true, it's true!
- Very well, Hercules.
- Very, very well.
- But there's one thing you can never
take away from me.
- My eyelashes.
- It's the love you gave to me.
The love we shared together.
Not even your Iole can ever take that
away from me.
- Don't speak to me of Iole.
We're leaving this island.
- As you wish, Hercules of Thebes.
- I want my record collection back.
- I will see that you and your friend
get away safely, but go quickly
before I change my mind!
- Just don't change your dress.
♫ The minute she walked out the door ♫
- Hercules happens to be alive,
but Ulysses, I'm sure
that if he were alive,
he would get to us somehow.
- Dismiss your men.
I want to be alone with my guests.
- But, but the invitation
said orgy to follow.
- Seeing you're already here, scram.
- Hey, Herc.
- Oh, hi, Dale.
(soft footsteps)
Okay, who's got a clue about the plot?
Anyone, Bob, Rick?
Ted, you've got the hat, you must know.
- Good night, everybody!
The Greek audiences are
the greatest audiences
in the world!
- Goodbye, Laërtes.
Goodbye, my Greek friends.
Hercules will depart with you.
Zandone will accompany you to the landing.
- Zamboni?
- You know how my boy is.
Tell me, please!
- Hey, look out, Father!
- Hey, Aunt Carol gave us that vase.
- Before they leave the island!
Come on!
(loud crash)
- Hey, no, not the bass fiddle table!
- That pledge is really something.
(suspenseful music)
- Kill them!
Kill them all!
But spare me, Hercules.
- This is an aphrodisiac for her.
- What isn't an aphrodisiac for her?
(suspenseful music)
- Hercules, table for eight.
- Oh (chuckles).
- Oh, come on, he's throwing
a giant chocolate bunny!
- Wow!
- Hey, we heard there
was fighting in here.
- Yes, it's Hercules,
history's first high-energy
prop comic.
- Hey, look at this!
Woo!
- The Hercules chess set,
send for yours today,
60609.
- There's a guy back there
throwing stuff, watch out!
(grunting)
- Uh, somebody want to...
Wait, I'll get it, Ulysses, jeez!
- Are we locked in or out?
- Yes.
- Ulysses, what about
that story you told me?
- Okay, let's see.
Oh, that's not the one you wanted, sorry.
(suspenseful music)
- I went through the bushes into the...
Oh, this isn't a flashback anymore.
(suspenseful music)
- Hmm. Neat, huh?
They're great.
But really pricey, guys.
Don't touch anything
you don't want to buy.
- A couple of thousand of years from now,
their arms and noses
will all be broken off.
(suspenseful music)
- Why, look, Hercules!
It was all ready for you.
- Come, let's hurry.
There's still time to end up here.
- It wasn't supposed to
be ready until Thursday.
- This way.
- I don't know where he's going.
I'm just following.
- Quickly, before the door closes!
- Wow, this is just
like Super Mario World.
♫ Du du dudu dudu dudu ♫
- Jump!
- Oh!
- I'm too old to jump.
- Use your mantle.
That's right.
- But white men can't jump.
- Hey, hey, that's not part of the...
Oh.
- Yeah, take your time.
No rush, pops.
- It's around my neck (choking).
(suspenseful music)
- Oh!
- Ow, oh, no, I'm okay, it's cool.
I'm fine.
- I hear the sound of the sea.
It's coming from there.
- Yeah, I guess the sea's in that corner.
♫ Tan ta nan ♫
- We're all safe now.
- Except for the oil slick.
- Better swim out to her.
- Well, when in Rome.
- Swim, did you say?
I don't know how!
- I'll carry you.
You'll be all right.
- Yeah.
Go to the sea, old man!
- You know, Deborah
Kerr and Burt Lancaster
must be around here somewhere.
- Yeah, put some clothes
back on, Gramps, ew.
- No, I prefer to return--
- Come on into the water!
- No, I'm not afraid.
The doctors haven't discovered
a cure for rheumatism!
(loud laughter)
- What's he talking about?
- Oh, no.
(soft music)
♫ I love Hercules
♫ And his giant pecs
♫ I'll never ever
♫ I'll just die ♫
- Well, this scene ought
to raise a few eyebrows.
♫ I'll end my life
♫ For Hercules ♫
- I'm ready for my closeup, Mr. DeMille.
♫ I'll just die in a pool of milk ♫
- Oh, though she was spooky,
I kind of miss her already.
♫ Hercules ♫
- Pull!
- Oh, oops, little bird
poopie on your back.
- Now your mother won't worry.
- My mother? No.
Mother's so courageous,
she won't be upset.
I sent it for Penelope.
- Your boy is growing.
- Yes, the youngsters today
think only about girls.
- Not me, sir.
- I'll never be able to repay you.
- Just go on being our friend.
- I wouldn't worry about it.
And you'll see how long we'll
be your guests in Thebes.
- We may not even go back to Ithaca.
(loud laughter)
- Shut up, shut up, shut up!
- How long to the island anyway?
- About 20 days, I think.
- That's much longer than we meant, too.
- Oh, 20 days.
- I forgot to file my quarterly.
- The time limit is up.
Polynices is at the gate of Thebes.
Iole.
I've been tricked by the gods!
She's in the hands of that madman!
- Hoist sail and pull ahead!
(mechanical noise)
- Uh, Joel, can we talk
to your for a second here?
- Sure, guys.
What's up?
How are you doing?
- Well, Crow and I were
playing cartoon tag
down in Quadrant 12 and we got
to talking about this movie,
and we can't seem to
figure out why the Herc
is hanging around that weird lady's place.
- Yeah, it's no big deal, but
we thought we'd pop in here
and have you settle it for us.
- I understand.
It's no problem.
Well, this far into the film, we know that
Hercules drank the
waters of forgetfulness.
He doesn't know who he is, so he's staying
with the nice lady.
- Oh, no, duh, I know that.
I guess what I'm asking is,
what does he do there all day?
- He eats.
- Well, he can't eat all day.
He's got to be doing something else.
- He's visiting her.
He visits.
- He's not caving in.
- Oh, come on, Joel.
You visit with your aunt, and this woman
is nobody's aunt.
What are they doing
when they're, you know,
snuggling and kind of kissing and stuff,
and then the scene fades out?
- Hmm, telling secrets.
Secrets.
- Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay.
So, Hercules, big, rugged, muscly Hercules
gets up at, say, oh, eleven-thirty,
eats some bread, fruit, some
manna, and some spiced wine.
- And don't forget the nymphs.
- Right, right, brought
to him by one of the six
or seven hundred scantily-clad nymphs.
He has some spiced wine, takes a sauna,
gets a massage.
Then the nice lady who's
letting him stay there rent-free
comes over with scented
oils, says some gushy stuff
to him, they cuddle and smooch,
and they tell each other some secrets.
And then what?
- He fixes her dishwasher.
I don't know.
You guys have seen as much
of the movie as I have.
Who's hungry?
- Joel, you seem nervous.
Is there something you're not telling us?
- Yep, Joel, I think
it's time to come clean
on the whole Hercules
in bondage thing here.
- It's Hercules Unchained, Tom,
and I think you two bots are old enough
to know the truth about this.
Hercules is the nice
lady's live-in dentist.
- Ah.
Hey!
What a ripoff.
- That's not fair!
- Look, come on, you guys.
Eat your raisins.
You go on ahead.
I have to iron this out.
They're nature's candy.
- No, I don't want it.
- Okay.
Catch it, come on.
Are you ready?
(upbeat music)
- Hercules--
- Live-in dentist, duh!
- I think I know what.
- Your woman is going to
provide a spectacle for us
till the day I get you.
She'll be held for the tigers.
- The Detroit Tigers?
- No.
- Any others?
Stand back now!
Here's my answer, Polynices.
Look at your supporters.
- But they're not wearing supporters.
- You'll be next.
Yes, you're next!
- You're next to the statue!
(loud screaming)
- Boo!
(horses neighing)
- Oops.
(maniacal laughter)
- Say what you want.
The guy's got a great sense of humor.
(maniacal laughter)
- Weird, really weird.
- It wasn't really funny.
Must be some obscure
Greek observational humor
or something, I don't know.
- Well, to each his own.
- Yup.
♫ Sing around the campfire
♫ Join the campfire Greeks ♫
- Eteocles mustn't see you.
He waits only for that in
order to kill your wife.
She'll die before your eyes.
It'll be the climax to everything.
- Okay, okay!
- Throw her to the tigers.
- Or the Euphrates.
It doesn't make much difference.
- Does that bug you?
- We're prepared to help you, Hercules.
We'll do whatever you want.
But you must be careful.
- You'll have to speak
at your sister's school
on career day.
- There goes one of the
dumbest guys you'll ever meet.
(loud thud)
- Ouch!
- Send all our forces against one
because the Thebans are there.
It's only because you
want to meet face-to-face
with Eteocles.
- It would be better to have the attack
come as a surprise.
- My brother is made but he is ingenious.
You can be sure about
our going into battle
when the Thebans have
the sun in their eyes.
- Oh, for the clarity of --
- Don't you count on my
people in the city anymore?
- Well, our impression is
that they're eliminated.
- There is still a great
many who are loyal to me.
- Our information is to the contrary.
- The people want Creon, they say.
- That isn't true!
I guarantee you about it.
- And who guarantees us about you?
- Mercenary from Thebes bearing a message.
- Mystery guest, enter
and sign in, please!
- Now, you guys are supposed
to stop bogging down
the movie.
- Eteocles to speak to you, Polynices.
He offers to settle the rule of Thebes
with a duel, just you and he alone.
That is why I bring this to you now.
- It's our GED.
- A duel?
Not a bad idea.
- We could get Dennis Weaver.
- How about it, Polynices?
- I must think about it.
- It means peace now, Polynices.
- Of course.
It's much better to duel.
- Not afraid by any chance, Polynices?
- But who'll assure us
the bargain's respected?
- All of us Thebans.
I'm only telling you that we're weary
of these quarrels, of the bloodshed.
- We we we we?
- We we we we.
- But you may lose, Polynices.
You may die.
Will they get out of the city
and return to their houses?
Do you promise that?
- I'm chilly.
Would you get me a wrap?
- I assure you.
- I'm bald.
(water splashing)
- Crayfish, ouch.
Now that divides the kiddie
pool from the adult pool.
(water splashing)
(suspenseful music)
♫ Du du du du du du ♫
- He's getting the bends.
- Good one.
- Tonight on Garrison Gorillas.
The ragtag band of rebels
are taking on the Greeks.
- Hey, the water's warm here.
Herc!
- Oh, jeez!
- Aesculapius!
- You're Aesculapius; I'm better.
- Oh, gods, please protect me.
- It's the newest sport: grandpa dunking.
- He's going to rust like everything now.
(suspenseful music)
The first stair master.
- Wasn't that Hercules?
(loud clanging)
- Hey, we're just trying
to send you baskets.
(loud clanging)
- Whoa! Whoa, guys!
- Ooh!
- They're into it.
- They want their towels back.
- Hey, anybody seen my
social security check?
I must have dropped it.
- 'Cause he's old, you see.
- Oh, criminy.
I wandered under the Spartacus set, ah!
- Uh, sir, we're closed.
(gate creaking)
- Hello, guys?
Hey, this isn't funny anymore.
D'oh!
(loud laughter)
- Hey, Hercules has a
big smelly butt (laughs).
(loud growling)
♫ He's a man-eater ♫
(loud laughter)
- I gotta admit, it's funny.
(loud growling)
Nice camera work.
Good tiger's butt there.
- Hey, didn't he pull a thorn out of that
tiger's paw?
- Ooh!
(loud growling)
- Hobbes, get off of me!
- Come on, pretend you're biting me.
I work for tips.
- Nice kitty.
(loud growling)
(loud laughter)
- Aw.
- You killed my dad,
you freaked-out maniac!
- I'm Charleton Heston's contact.
(loud laughter)
- I'm hungry for a manwich (chuckles).
(loud growling)
- Cat scratch fever!
- Owser!
(loud growling)
- You drop that ball.
Drop that ball, drop it!
Drop it!
Drop it, drop it!
(loud growling)
- Hi, we just thought we'd stop by
and see what's--
(loud grunting)
- Oh, look, it's the Smurfs
versus these kids here.
- Take your time, Ulysses.
(loud growling)
- Aw, boo! Boo!
- I hate that.
- He hit Big Jake.
(loud grunting)
- Spare the rod, spoil the child.
Spare the rod and spoil the child.
- Oh, it says pull.
(suspenseful music)
- Look, Herc's got a rip.
(loud crash)
- Knock, knock! Ha!
(upbeat music)
(suspenseful music)
- Gee, you know, if somebody
had invented boxing,
They'd save a lot of time here.
(loud clanging)
- Oh, look!
- Do you want to go?
- Yeah, sure. Your place?
(horses neighing)
- Oh, I'll be right back.
I forgot something.
I'll catch you in the flip flop, okay?
(loud cheer)
- Now, it's just me and you, mano a mano.
- Tonight it's Abe Agoda
versus James Whitmore
in a battle to the death.
(loud clanging)
- You know, there's no bad
seats in this stadium, huh?
- You know, I was just
wondering where Hercules went.
- I wonder where the movie went.
(loud clanging)
- Oh!
- Oh, you cut me, you jerk!
- Hello, my name is Inigo Montoya.
You killed my father.
Prepare to die.
- And fighting over who
had that hairstyle first.
- I look like Lucille!
- No, I look like Lucille!
(crying out)
- Now he's the knight of
the living dead (chuckles).
- Ooh.
(maniacal laughter)
- This guy finds the
funny side of everything.
- Thank you.
Now, for my next trick, I need a volunteer
from the audience.
- Thebans, pray to the
gods because at last
Eteocles has won the day
and is victorious!
- He's no fun.
He fell right over.
- What a letdown.
- Aw.
- And now, a prayer.
- Now, I suppose I've got to go clean up,
for crying out loud.
(horse neighing)
I know, I feel the same way, horse.
- Come on, get up.
Still gotta go to school, dummy.
- The redhead is dead.
- He was as stupid as his brother.
They deserve to end this way.
- He learned too late that
man is a feeling creature,
and because of it, the
greatest in the universe.
He learned too late for himself that men
have to make their own way and--
- Yeah, yeah.
- Hercules, do you see this?
Well, I shall celebrate this victory.
She's in my house now,
and I'm going there.
- And I've got cable!
- Uh, what time should I come over?
Do you want me to bring something?
- Get to your posts!
- Get my purse?
(suspenseful music)
- You know, this is like I, Claudius,
only it's not good at all.
(suspenseful music)
- You know, they really are talented.
They put on such a great show, you know.
They give 110% over there, you know.
- Oh, yeah.
- Let's break off and start another movie!
- Ha, look.
It looks like they've
got the leftover parts
from an airplane model.
- It's the world's largest chess set.
- It's a traveling rest stop.
♫ Du du dum, dum dum ♫
- Why, look at that.
The Thebans are abandoning their defenses.
- Oh, do you see that?
- They must be surrendering the town.
- Looks like they brought the
whole darn town with them!
- It's Ted Koppel's head, look out!
- Ooh! Aah!
- Hey, come on and
interrupt, you gladiators!
- Ladies and gentlemen, Elvis Presley!
(imitating funky music)
- And each float is made of 75,000
individual fresh flowers put in place.
- Yup, I'm the title character.
That's me, pretty much.
Herc, your friend, hi.
(suspenseful music)
- Hey, does anybody have an idea
what we're doing here?
- I thought you knew!
- No!
(suspenseful music)
- Oh, thank you.
- This kind of reminds me
of The Empire Strikes Back,
except it's not very good.
- Yeah, not really.
(horses neighing)
- Oh!
♫ Pum pum pududum pum pum pum pum
♫ Pum dududum dum du ♫
(loud screaming)
- Hercules, those are our guys, you idiot!
(suspenseful music)
- Oh, now here comes the Boston marathon!
- Forward the cavalry!
- That's not my department,
Captain Reynolds!
- Yeah, yeah, I know.
Once more, under the breach, I know.
(horses neighing)
- Boo!
- I hate this!
- I'm calling Betty White.
- And I'm calling Tippi Hedron.
- And I'm calling Brigitte Bardot.
- Black Beauty, Flicka, Scout,
Trigger, Secretariat, no!
- It's like the end of
the Mel Brooks movie.
(horses neighing)
(loud screaming)
- Oo-hoo, that's good tower.
- Checkmate.
- Oh, look at the
Sisters of Saint Francis.
- Last day of school is always like this.
- Nutty.
- And die, thank you.
- Okay, everybody, off the set.
We're trying to clear the
set for the end of the movie.
Please leave the set now, thank you.
- Buh-bye! (chuckles)
- Bye now.
- Epilogue.
- Spalding Gray?
- The Thebes took revenge
on Oedipus and his sons too.
- And his friend Chopper is real fun.
- For inciting the gods.
Now with these flames,
they purify our city
and those who shall stay.
- Or something like that, I think.
You'll have to excuse me.
I'm really hungover.
- Oh, honey, about all
that boinking and boinking
that I did on the island,
well, it's nothing.
- How much you've suffered, Iole.
The gods have placed many
obstacles against us,
and there will be others.
- Yeah, well, you're
sleeping on the couch, Herc.
- I hope we shall withstand.
Somehow the gods will be kind
if we just love one another.
- Are they in heaven?
- Now, Herc, no more business trips, okay?
- This is the end of the
story of forgetfulness.
Those who watch of it will die of boredom.
Ah!
Mm, stinky.
(mechanical noise)
- Hey, Joelster, why these kind of movies?
- Well, that's a good question, Gypsy.
However, there aren't any simple answers.
- Well, yes, there are.
- I think maybe it's a cultural thing.
You know, the post-war era.
- Right, that's exactly right, Crow.
You know, western culture had a real need
during the Cold War for
a fantastic spectacle.
- Yeah, spectacles!
- Yeah, it's true.
After Liz Taylor accepted
over a million dollars
for a role in Cleopatra, you know,
big-budget blockbusters
became the coin of the realm.
- No, wrong, guys, wrong.
- I was thinking more along the lines
of European indignation
towards post-war conservatism
and sexual repression which translated
onto the screen in the big sweaty guys
pushing girls around.
- Crow, you are so high.
- No, come on.
Crow's got a point.
Without sex, would Hercules Unchained
have even been made?
- Joseph Campbell.
- Huh?
- Joseph Campbell?
- Oh, I think what our bright young friend
is trying to remind us of is
the need for myth, you know,
the collective dream.
- Oh, yeah, yeah.
There's a need for gods and heroes.
I remember that Joseph
Campbell said something
in one of those books of his with masks
and stuff in it, and that this thing
you're supposed to do.
- Wrong, wrong.
- Come on, I think we can probe deeper
into the phenomenal--
- Phenomenological.
- Yeah.
I think we can probe deeper
into the phenomenological basis
for a Hercules experience.
- Discarding the classical
dualistic view, of course.
- How do you figure?
- Well, Gypsy, every phenomenon belongs
to a regional anthology
by virtue of its essence.
- Look, I'll make it easy for all of you!
Joseph E. Levine picked these turkeys up
after a sagging European
box drove the price
way down that he dumped
right into America,
then amassed a distribution deal,
and made a fortune, okay?
- You're wrong.
- Oh.
- Philistine.
- Tom.
- Well, well, it's true.
Am I right, sirs?
Come on, back me up on this.
- Yeah.
- Oh, well, Steve, is that right?
- Huh?
Yeah, I guess so.
I mean, there are these guys in suits
that used to drive up the coast
and check on us every now and then.
I didn't really get to meet them much.
I was usually up on the cliff,
drinking that wine they got there.
It's really cheap.
It's about 13 cents a bottle.
- Thank you, Steve.
- Yeah, no problem.
- Well, until next time.
Push the button, Frank.
- Say, I dig your hair, man.
- Frank!
- Could I have your autograph?
- Oh, okay.
Are you in any relation to Keanu Reeves?
(slow music)